=A Puppetry=
= دمية =
=Episode 7=
= الحلقة 7 =
I heard
سمعت
there are some big names
هناك بعض الأسماء الكبيرة
coming to Mai Prefecture.
قادمًا إلى محافظة ماي.
We can look forward to it.
يمكننا أن نتطلع إلى ذلك.
Do you mean
هل تعني
theatre troupes who come for
فرق المسرح الذين يأتون
the puppetry festival?
مهرجان الدمى؟
Yes, it is.
نعم إنه كذلك.
What a shame.
يا للعار.
The Chen Theater Troupe
فرقة مسرح تشن
all died in a fire.
ماتوا جميعا في حريق.
I suppose
أفترض
I'll never get the chance
لن تسنح لي الفرصة ابدا
to watch a good puppet show again.
لمشاهدة عرض جيد للدمى مرة أخرى.
Oh, that's not true.
أوه ، هذا ليس صحيحًا.
But I heard successor
لكنني سمعت خليفة
of the Chen Theater Troupe,
من فرقة مسرح تشين ،
Liu Xiaoxiao,
ليو شياوكسياو ،
survived.
نجا.
She was tricked into prostitution.
تم خداعها في الدعارة.
Successor of the Chen Theater Troupe?
خليفة فرقة مسرح تشين؟
Prostitution?
بغاء؟
How could that be possible?
كيف يمكن أن يكون ذلك ممكنا؟
Even if
حتى لو
it's the apprentice,
إنه المتدرب ،
how would she become a courtesan?
كيف تصبح مومس؟
Don't talk nonsense.
لا تتحدث عن هراء.
Butler.
بتلر.
Take the reward money to this musician
خذ أموال المكافأة لهذا الموسيقي
and send him off now.
وأرسله الآن.
The pitiful Chen Theatre Troupe
فرقة مسرح تشن المثيرة للشفقة
encounters such a stroke of bad luck
يواجه مثل هذا الحظ السيئ
in bad times.
في الأوقات العصيبة.
(Chunman Brothel)
(بيت دعارة تشونمان)
Geez.
الجيز.
Why didn't they give me some staple food?
لماذا لم يعطوني بعض الطعام الأساسي؟
Wonder
يتعجب
how's Song Keyang doing now?
كيف حال Song Keyang الآن؟
Can she manage to find him?
هل تستطيع أن تجده؟
Liu Xiaoxiao.
ليو شياوكسياو.
Song Keyang.
سونغ كيانغ.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Are you alright?
هل انت بخير؟
I'm good.
أنا بخير.
Keep your voice down.
حافظ على صوتك منخفضًا.
Close the door.
أغلق الباب.
I was talking about you just now
كنت أتحدث عنك الآن
and you turn up right after.
وتحضر مباشرة بعد ذلك.
Just now,
الآن،
Madam Hua and I have reached an agreement.
لقد توصلت أنا وسيدتي هوا إلى اتفاق.
Madam Hua?
سيدتي هوا؟
Later,
في وقت لاحق،
you go upstairs
تصعد الطابق العلوي
to straighten
لتصويب
- Madam Hua. - everything up.
- سيدتي هوا.  - كل شيء.
It's you, Mr. Song.
أنت يا سيد سونغ.
So that
لهذا السبب
I can sneak in here to check on you.
يمكنني التسلل هنا للاطمئنان عليك
Do you come here as
هل أتيت إلى هنا بصفتك
- a musician? - A musician.
- موسيقي؟  - موسيقي.
This is...
هذا هو...
Do check on it if it's the thing you want.
تحقق منه إذا كان هو الشيء الذي تريده.
As expected of Troupe Leader Sun.
كما هو متوقع من قائد الفرقة صن.
This puppet is vividly drawn
هذه الدمية مرسومة بوضوح
and can be manipulated smoothly.
ويمكن التلاعب بها بسلاسة.
As for now,
أما الآن ،
we just need to think of
نحن فقط بحاجة للتفكير فيه
how to let people know
كيفية إعلام الناس
that Chen Theatre Troupe
أن فرقة مسرح تشين
is having a performance here.
يحظى بأداء هنا.
I
أنا
can manage this easily.
يمكن إدارة هذا بسهولة.
It's all taken care of.
كل شيء يتم الاعتناء به.
(Puppet Show)
(عرض الدمى)
What's this?
ما هذا؟
Kids.
أطفال.
Pass this
مرر هذا
to misters and ladies
للسيدات والسيدات
when you meet them.
عندما تقابلهم.
Do speak sweetly and softly to them.
تحدث معهم بلطف ورفق.
Whoever finishes handing out the flyers first
من ينتهي من توزيع النشرات أولاً
gets a gift.
يحصل على هدية.
Also, I'll give you sweets.
أيضا ، سأقدم لك الحلويات.
Alright?
على ما يرام؟
- Alright.
- على ما يرام.  - على ما يرام.
Big sister, this is for you.
الأخت الكبرى ، هذا لك.
Have a look at it.
إلقاء نظرة على ذلك.
Looking at this situation,
بالنظر إلى هذا الموقف ،
I've hit
لقد ضربت
today's KPI target.
هدف KPI اليوم.
Oh my.
يا بلادي.
I'm really
أنا حقا
an unremarkable genius.
عبقرية غير ملحوظة.
Good wine needs no bush.
النبيذ الجيد لا يحتاج إلى شجيرة.
Later,
في وقت لاحق،
the place must be full of audience.
يجب أن يكون المكان مليئًا بالجمهور.
(Ever since he's appeared,)
(منذ أن ظهر)
(everything just goes smoothly.)
(كل شيء يسير بسلاسة.)
Oh, right.
صحيح.
Song Keyang.
سونغ كيانغ.
Do you know
هل تعرف
these people are so bad?
هؤلاء الناس سيئون جدا؟
They only give me
هم فقط يعطونني
tasteless food every day.
طعام لا طعم له كل يوم.
I can hardly eat them.
أنا بالكاد أستطيع أكلهم.
That's why I'm here for you.
لهذا أنا هنا من أجلك.
Eat up.
أكل.
It smells nice.
رائحتها لطيفة.
I have never tried this before.
لم أجرب هذا من قبل.
It's the lazy braised rice.
إنه الأرز المطهو ​​ببطء.
Tastes good, right?
طعمه جيد ، صحيح؟
Delicious.
لذيذ.
(It seems I've cooked it well.)
(يبدو أنني طهوه جيدًا.)
(- She is easily satisfied.) - Xiaoxiao.
(- إنها راضية بسهولة) - شياو تشياو.
Xiaoxiao.
شياوكسياو.
Have you prepared everything you need?
هل أعددت كل ما تحتاجه؟
Madam Hua.
سيدتي هوا.
What brings you here?
ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا؟
I'm just coming to check on you.
أنا قادم فقط للاطمئنان عليك.
Nothing.
لا شئ.
I'm just looking around.
انا فقط ابحث.
Since the things are prepared,
بما أن الأشياء معدة ،
you can prepare
يمكنك التحضير
for receiving guests now.
لاستقبال الضيوف الآن.
Receiving guests?
استقبال الضيوف؟
I've spent so much money advertising you
لقد أنفقت الكثير من المال في الإعلان عنك
just for today.
فقط لليوم.
You
أنت
better prepare for it well.
أفضل الاستعداد لها بشكل جيد.
I'll get going.
سأذهب.
Song Keyang.
سونغ كيانغ.
(I'll handle this. No worries.)
(سأتعامل مع هذا. لا تقلق.)
(The day of the Puppet Festival)
(يوم مهرجان الدمى)
Xiaoxiao.
شياوكسياو.
What if
ماذا إذا
my performance goes well today
يسير أدائي جيدًا اليوم
and...
و...
And someone
وشخص ما
redeems you.
يعوضك.
Right?
حق؟
I've prepared 30 taels.
لقد أعددت 30 تيل.
It's enough for redemption.
يكفي للخلاص.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Everything is under my control.
كل شيء تحت سيطرتي.
All you need to do
كل ما عليك القيام به
is to perform the puppet show well
هو أداء عرض الدمى بشكل جيد
without worries.
دون قلق.
You can count on me.
يمكنك الاعتماد علي.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
(Rod Pupper) Welcome to the Annual Puppet Festival
(رود بوبر) مرحبًا بكم في مهرجان الدمى السنوي
in Mai Prefecture.
(رود بوبر) في محافظة ماي.
Up next, the performer representing Chunman Brothel
بعد ذلك ، الممثل الذي يمثل Chunman Brothel
is Liu Xiaoxiao.
هو Liu Xiaoxiao.
♪To commemorate the past, the people raise their glass♪
لإحياء ذكرى الماضي ، يرفع الناس زجاجهم
Bravo!
أحسنت!
♪But the blissful moment still hasn't come♪
♪ لكن اللحظة السعيدة لم تأت بعد ♪
♪The twigs of the mimosa tree fold under the weather♪
تطوى أغصان شجرة الميموزا تحت الطقس ♪
♪The heavy rain rinses♪
شطف المطر الغزير ♪
Please give your Chinese Redbud
من فضلك أعط Redbud الصينية الخاصة بك
(Chinese Redbud) to your favourite puppeteer of the day.
(Redbud الصينية) لمحرك الدمى المفضل لديك اليوم.
(People give the flower) Bravo!
(الناس يعطون الزهرة) برافو!
(to their favourite puppeteer of Annual Puppet Show in Mai Prefecture.)
(لمحرك الدمى المفضل لديهم في عرض الدمى السنوي في محافظة ماي).
♪A broken heart lets the story fades away♪
♪ قلب مكسور يجعل القصة تتلاشى
Bravo!
أحسنت!
♪Who can rescue me?♪
♪ من ينقذني؟
♪I can still remember how beautiful the thimbleberry bloomed♪
♪ ما زلت أتذكر كم هي جميلة أزهر ثيمبلبيري ♪
♪When will we meet again after this separation?♪
متى نلتقي مرة أخرى بعد هذا الفراق؟
♪The language of flowers cannot answer the questions my heart poses♪
لغة الزهور لا تجيب على الأسئلة التي يطرحها قلبي
♪It can only sway with the flame♪
يمكن أن تتأرجح فقط مع اللهب
♪The dusk outside the window is spreading♪
♪ الغسق خارج النافذة ينتشر
♪The lanterns light up with anticipation♪
الفوانيس تضيء بترقب
♪The sea of lights illuminates the entire theatre♪
♪ بحر الأضواء ينير المسرح بأكمله
♪The galaxy sprawls across the sky♪
المجرة تمتد عبر السماء ♪
♪The moon shows itself♪
القمر يظهر نفسه ♪
♪Gazing at the myriad lives♪
التحديق في حياة لا تعد ولا تحصى ♪
♪The bell chimes and the lady dances♪
يدق الجرس والسيدة ترقص
♪Her movements are mysterious and graceful♪
حركاتها غامضة ورشيقة ♪
♪A woman can solicit cheers and applause too♪
♪ يمكن للمرأة أن تلتمس الهتافات والتصفيق أيضًا ♪
♪Chatters fill the well-lit hall♪
♪ الدردشة تملأ القاعة المضاءة جيدًا
♪Holding a red candle by the stage♪
♪ عقد شمعة حمراء على خشبة المسرح ♪
♪Witnessing the blooming and wilting, oh, the freedom♪
مشاهدة التفتح والذبول يا الحرية
♪The theater welcomes you♪
المسرح يرحب بك ♪